我妈把这称之为一生中最棒的
Mother called it the greatest
却又是最恐怖的时刻
and most terrifying moment in her life.
他提到克莱夫
He said "Karev."
站在手术台的一端
Standing at the head of the surgical table,
心知肚明病人的生命系于自己一人之手
Knowing that a patient's life  depends on you and you alone...
-他提名克莱夫  -太好了
-你确定  -是的
- Are you sure?  - Yeah.
你真的确定
You're "sure" sure?
每位医生都梦寐以求
It's what we all dream about.
因为首先获得主刀手术资格的人
Because the first person that gets to fly solo in the O.R.
必定是最优秀的
Kind of a badass.
斯蒂文斯  他提名斯蒂文斯
Stevens! He said "Stevens."
到底是谁  你个蠢材  斯蒂文斯还是克莱夫
Well, which is it, moron, Stevens or Karev?
你们居然笨到相信这些傻瓜
This is stupid. You guys are gonna trust these imbeciles
-会知道主刀手术的人选  -你是不是不爽
- To tell you who's getting the solo surgery?  - Is this hard for you,
被剥夺了主刀手术资格
Being banned from the solo surgery?
-你心里一定很不爽  -说得好  我顶你
- It must be really hard for you. - Ooh, a mean streak. I like it.
他也许会改变主意  谁都知道他善变
He may change his mind. He's been known to change his mind.
别再说了
Please don't do that.
你们还是好好祈祷自己被选中吧
You guys go ahead and, uh, will yourselves to be voted in.
-使出杀手锏  -格蕾
- Use "the secret."  - Grey!
主任提名格蕾
Grey. Uh, the chief said "Grey."
怎么  拜托  这太假了
What? Come on. This is bogus.
你们才知道呢  史帝夫又不会读唇语
You're just figuring that out? Steve is not a lip-reader.
实习生里没有人懂唇语
None of the interns are lip-readers.
你们还是乖乖等着主治医生的投票吧
You just have to wait for the attendings to vote
就像我赢的那次一样
Just like we did when I won.
你赢得了主刀手术资格
You won your solo surgery?
我不觉得你有什么好吃惊的  杨医生
I'm just gonna pretend you didn't feel the need to ask me that question, Yang.
当然是我赢  我超棒
Of course I won. I was good.
我没切断过左室辅助装置的线
I didn't cut l-Vad wires...
也没把手伸进病人体内拿炸弹
Or put my hand in bomb-y body cavities
也没让我的实习生拿自己开刀
Or have my interns operating on themselves.
我很特别
I was special. Huh!
我是个年轻有为的黑人医生  人人都知道
I was young, gifted and black, and everybody knew it.
主治医生们知道  主任也知道
The attendings knew it. The chief knew it.
我不用装作懂唇语的样子
I didn't have to act like I could read lips.
只要安心做我的本职工作
Just go about my work calmly,
然后等着被选中
And waited for my name to get called.
有结果了
okay. It's done.
这次是谁  海伦·凯勒吗
Oh, whatever, Helen Keller.
这次是真的
No, I'm serious.
主任让我来宣布他们的决定
The chief sent me. They made their choice.
是谁
Who is it?
就是你
It's you.
我很高兴地宣布首次(住院医师)主刀手术
I am happy to announce that the first solo surgery
将于今晚进行
Will take place tonight--
膝下截肢手术  病人患有骨癌
A below-The-Knee amputation, bone cancer.
-可怜的家伙  -2212房的克林·斯沃思先生
- Poor bastard.  - Mr. Collinsworth in 2212.
-不是阑尾手术  -用锯子干活  太好了
- No appy? - Saw action. Sweet.
挑选完成主刀手术的医生
Choosing who gets the first solo surgery
不仅在于谁的能力最强
Isn't just about who has the best surgical skills
或是谁在手术室呆的时间最长
Or who's logged the most hours in the O.R.
而是我们所给予的高度信任
It's about the highest form of trust--
信任到将病人的生命
The trust to put a patient's life
交到一位住院医生手中
into one of our resident's hands.
这次是我印象中唯一一次
And for the first time that I can recall,
所有主治医生意见一致
Every single attending picked the same person.
就是杨医生
Dr. Yang.
然而  杨医生丧失了候选资格
However, Dr. Yang is out of the running.
因此主刀手术的决定权交给她来决定
She is going to pick the winner instead.
杨医生会于下午4点前
Dr. Yang will post her decision
在手术安排表上写下决定
on the O.R. Board at 4:00 p.M.
另外  鉴于全体实习生都处于禁术令中
Also, since your interns are still banned from the O.R.,
被提名者将有权
The winner will be allowed
选择一位同伴一起进行手术
To pick a fellow resident to scrub in with them.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
这是在折磨我
This is torture for me.
还没完呢
I'm not even done.
主任
Sir?
狄克逊医生回来了
Dr. Dixon's back.
今天由你陪着她
You'll be spending the day with her.
你要打动她
You will impress her.
你要想办法让医院打动她
And you will make sure this hospital impresses her.
今天过后
By the end of the day,
你得让她自愿成为本院的下任心脏科主任
I want that woman to be my next head of cardio.
如果她不干  就是你的责任  祝你好运
If she's not, I'll know who to blame. good luck
我们曾连续12小时一起握着牵引器
We held a retractor for 12 hours together.
你说过我的手小  适合手术  记得吗
You said I had small hands, good for surgery. Remember?
不记得  走开
No. Go away.
我在电梯里做过心脏手术
I operated on a heart in an elevator.
那是一年前了  欧麦利就是007
Look, that was over a year ago. O'malley's 007.
想想看  你要是选他
Think how poor your decision would look
-会被笑话的  -该你说了
- If you gave it to him. - Your turn.
我不懂你们有什么好争的
Mm. I don't know why you guys are even bothering.
我们都知道她会选谁
We all know who she's gonna pick.
她不会因为跟我铁而选我
She's not gonna pick me because I'm her best friend.
她选我是因为我最优秀
She's gonna pick me because I'm the best.
够了  你们这是在干什么
Okay, stop. Are you guys kidding me?
好吧  我会认真想的
Fine. I'll think about it.
你们回去工作吧
Just... go and do surgical things.
伊兹  你一起来吗  我们去门诊部
Iz, are you coming? We gotta go to the clinic.
现在是流感季节
Flu season fun.
当然
yeah. Um...
我过会儿就去
I... will catch up with you.
-我也是  -闭嘴
- Me, too.  - Shut up.
不是说你
Not you.
是说我的头  关上  就这样
My head... shut up.  you know?
如果我赢了  我会选你
When I win, you can scrub in for me.
阿历克斯  她不会选你的
A-Alex, she's not... not gonna pick you.
你要是赢了你也要选我
I'll scrub in for you, too, if you win,
但你不会赢  因为一定是我赢
Which you won't, because I will.
够了
Enough.
我得走了
I-I gotta go. Yeah.
克里斯蒂娜今天没跟我说过话
Cristina still hasn't talked to me,
这很正常  否则就糟了
Which is normal, except it's worse.
停职两周
Two weeks suspension,
她连骂都懒得骂了
And she hasn't even bothered to say one mean thing.
克莱夫叫我蠢材  这很好
Karev called me a moron, which is good.
住院医生们都没瞧过我一眼
Well, none of the residents even look at me.
-他们不可能恨我们  -我要去做爱
- The least they could do is hate us. - Well, I'm gonna get some sex.
-做爱让我放松下来  -别看着我
- Sex always makes me feel better. - Don't look at me.
也别看我
Me either.
想也别想
That makes three of us.
我明白了
I get it.
是我发起了秘密手术试验
I'm the one who organized a crazy cabal of secret cutter interns.
问题是  刚才有人让我找人做爱
The thing is, I've been advised to seek out sex
来摆脱内心的痛楚
As a way out of my sad predicament,
但我认为我还是学习要紧  所以
But I think I would rather just learn today, so...
你有什么主意吗
What do you say?
你和我
You, me--
你干嘛跟我谈做爱
Why are you talking about sex to me?
这样很不妥  我是你的老师
It's inappropriate. I'm your teacher.
我的工作是传授知识  我拥有双资格执照
I have things to teach-- double board certified things.
不  这正是我想说的
No, that was always--That's what I was talking about,
你教我医学知识
For--For you to teach me medicine.
-做爱只是玩笑话  -斯隆医生
- The--The sex was that-- That was a joke.  - Dr. Sloan.
我听说你要进行
um, I heard that you're performing
下咽部重建手术
A hypopharynx reconstruction today.
我会让她再次开口说话
I'm gonna make a woman speak again.
我也希望如此  我研究了一下这个手术
Well, let's hope. I read up on the surgery and--
-你研究我的手术  -这是你首次进行
- You read up on my surgery? - Since it's your first time performing
在我看来非常尖端的手术
What I understand to be a very cutting-edge surgery,
我想也许你需要帮手
I was hoping you might need an extra set of hands.
行  你可以加入我和格蕾医生
Fine. You can join Dr. Grey and me.
格蕾医生被禁止参加手术
Dr. Grey who's been banned from the O.R.?
她负责给我递咖啡
She's on cappuccino duty,
说起来  我还等着咖啡呢  格蕾医生
Which, Dr. Grey, I'm still waiting for.
马上来  谢谢
Right away. Thank you.
维吉尼亚·狄克逊医生
Dr. Virginia Dixon.
记录显示她半小时前就来了
It says she arrived over half an hour ago.
-她去哪了  -紧张什么?
- Where is she?  - Nervous?
什么  你来这里干什么  这里是心脏科
What? What are you doing here? This is the cardio wing.
-只欢迎心脏科医生  -我只是四处看看
- Only cardio gods allowed. I know. - I was just looking around,
-了解医院的其他地方  -就这么点儿地方
Getting to know other parts of the hospital. What else is there?
手术室  急诊室  餐厅
The O.R., the e.R. And the place with the food.
很多地方你还不知道
Somebody's got a lot to learn.
凯思林·帕特森
Kathleen Patterson.
5年前进行喉切除术
A laryngectomy five years ago
失去了说话能力
Resulted in the loss of her ability to speak.
过去5年内  凯思林尝试过多种手术
Kathleen's undergone several surgical attempts
希望能再次发声说话
To restore her voice in the past five years,
-都没能成功  -但这一次
- None have been successful.  - oh, oh, this time, though,
这一次  我们觉得很有希望
This time, uh, we have a good feeling about this.
对吗  亲爱的
Right, honey?
经过讨论  我们将从你的手臂取得供血
As discussed, I'll get the blood supply
并对你的软骨进行
From your arm and the cartilage...
-从你的  -凯思林
-From your... uh,  -Kathleen?
亲爱的
Honey?
Honey.
-和我说吧  -我将从她的手臂提取皮肤
-You can talk to me.  -I'll get the skin
和血液  从鼻子提取软骨
And the blood supply from her arm
来制造替代她咽喉的通话管
To construct a makeshift speaking tube,
也就是她的新嗓子
Which will become her new voice box.
当然你也要理解这个手术
-Now you should be aware there's a chance
-可能失败  -他很清楚这一点
-The procedure might not work.  -He's clear on that.
我只是提醒他不要抱太高的期望
I'm just reminding him not to get his hopes up.
还有任何疑问吗
Any other questions I can answer?
凯思林
Kathleen?
亲爱的
Honey?
告诉我一切关于克莱夫的事情
Tell me everything there is to know about Karev.
为什么
Why?
我是他的实习生  他是你屋子里最酷的那个
I'm his intern. He seems cool enough at your house,
虽然他女朋友
Though whatever he's got going
很诡异  一直自慰
With the girl who masturbates all the time--
我不发表评论
I don't like to judge--
但是职务上我是他的实习生
But still, officially, I'm his intern.
他是什么喜好
So what's his deal?
赛迪  在医院里我不能做你的朋友
Sadie, I can't be your friend in here.
我是说  我是住院医师  你是实习生
I mean, I'm a resident, and you're an intern.
你要自己去弄清楚
You're gonna have to figure out
怎样投其所好
How not to piss off Alex Karev yourself.
好吧  我知道了
Okay. I get it.
-非常好  -又无聊又丑
-Good.  -...boring and ugly.
那不是我的错
It wasn't my fault.
我必须告诉约翰他们去哪儿找我们
I had to tell John and those guys where to meet us.
我说过了我来告诉他们  你好好开车
I said I would do it, that way you could drive.
-我要告诉爸爸妈妈  -你敢我就杀了你
-I'm telling mom and dad.  -I'll kill you.
-姑娘们  冷静  -跟她说去  -闭嘴
-Girls, you need to calm down.  -Tell her! Shut up!
-什么情况  -姐妹  16岁15岁  把爸爸的车撞烂了
-what happened?  -Sisters, 16 and 15, crashed their dad's car, and that's
她们吵个不停  只了解这么多
All we know since they won't stop screaming at each other.
-告诉我你的名字  快  -别说  一句话都不许说
-We need your names, now.  -Don't tell her. Don't you say a word.
她叫好丽 安德森
Her name is Holly Anderson.
她边开车边发短信
She was driving  and texting while driving.
这有警官吗  我要控告她
Is there a police officer here? I would like to press charges.
-马屁精  死马屁精  -够了
-Oh, you suck-Up! You suck-Up ass face!  -okay, hey.
告诉我们电话  我们要通知家长
We need your number so we can call your parents.
-这儿  我已经接通了爸爸  -你这个婊子
-Here. I speed-Dialed my dad.  -You're such a bitch.
-你才是婊子  -难怪学校里的男生都讨厌你
-No, you are.  -No wonder all the boys in school hate you.
-让她们停下来  -闭嘴
-make it stop.  -shut up!
爸爸妈妈来了你就死定了
You are so dead when mom and dad show up.
-医生们还要再抢救你一次  -我恨你
The doctors are just gonna have to save you again.  -I hate you.
-我更恨你  -我恨你们两个
-I hate you more.  -I hate you both.
我知道你还觉得我是007
I know you still see me as 007,
但那已经是过去了
But that was day one.
之后我成长了  学习了
I've grown a lot since then and learned a lot.
大家都可以很聪明
You know, anyone can... can have brains
可以很有天赋  但关键是成长
Or anyone can have talent, but the key is to grow.
毋庸置疑  我的开始很糟
So sure, I had a rough start
我还重修了实习生
And I had to redo some of my intern year,
但是  这也造就了现在的我
But, you know, I came out the other side,
更聪明  更出色
Smarter, better.
最重要的是我学会永远不放弃
The important point is I never gave up,
因为我是个战士
Because I'm a fighter.
谢谢你
Thank you.
艾玛  我要去检查你的x光
Okay, Emma, I'm gonna have to check your x-Rays,
我觉得你的腿骨折了
But I think your leg's broken.
-你需要住院一段时间  -不  不
-You're gonna be off it for a while.  -No. No!
我不能错过成为美国会议的领袖
I can't miss my future leaders of America conference.
好丽
Holly!
艾玛  毕业前我都会老老实实学习
Emma, I'm gonna be grounded till graduation.
我要去华盛顿  我整整期待一年了
I was going to d.C. I've been waiting for this for a year.
爸妈为此花了2000块  不  2000块打了水漂了
Mom and dad spent 2 grand. No, they've now wasted 2 grand.
天啊  你这个傻子
Hey. God, you stupid baby!
够了  我要隔离你们俩
Hey, all right. You know, I'm separating you two.
听好  我会一直在这陪你
Listen, I've been here, lots.
你爸爸不会像你想象的那么生气
Your dad won't be as pissed as you think.
-只要你们没事就好  -他会杀了我  夺走一切
-He'll just be happy that you're safe.  -He'll kill me. He'll take away everything.
她的眼睛变成这样多长时间了
How long have her eyes been like that?
-她的眼睛  怎么了  -呼谢博德德
-Her eyes? What-  -Page Shepherd.
她可能颅骨基部破损
Tell him she might have a basilar skull fracture.
-赶快带她去做CT  -不好意思我没注意到
-Let's get her up to c.T., now.  -I didn't see. I'm sorry.
你会什么啊  等她需要鼓励时候我再叫你
You can do scut. I'll call you when she needs another pep talk.
-她去哪儿  -做点检测
-Where is she going?  -Just to run a few tests.
好极了  把她弄出去  弄出去
Good! Get her out of here! Take her away!
快点死吧你
I hope you die!
有人有大麻烦了
Ooh. Somebody's in big trouble.
忘记开门了还是忘记派人过来了
Did you forget to open it or did you forget to staff it?
都有  对不起  对不起大家
Both. I'm sorry. I'm sorry, everybody.
我去拿钥匙马上回来
I will be right back with the keys.
顺便找几个护士过来
Might want to get some nurses while you're at it. Oh.
这经常发生吗  要是经常的话
So does this happen a lot? because if it does,
你可是让我的诊所声名狼藉啊
You're kinda giving my clinic a bad name.
想嘲笑我  可爱  真可爱
You're mocking me now? Sweet. Very sweet.
狄克逊医生  你在这儿啊
Dr. Dixon, there you are.
我是杨医生
I'm Dr. Yang.
好吧  今天我被分配到您的手下
Great. Well, I've been assigned to work with you today.
我刚刚去心脏实验室找您
I was in the cardio lab looking for you.
很抱歉现在才找到您
I'm so sorry it took me so long.
手术板上有空白
There's a blank spot on this board.
有个手术缺少外科医生
There's a surgery but no surgeon.
我想做手术  可惜是截肢手术
I would like to do a surgery, but it's an amputation.
从住院医师开始我就没做过截肢了
I haven't done an amputation since my residency.
这  那确实
That's... it's really hard to...
确实
Um, that...
你的口吃是长期性病理的
Is your stuttering pathological and persistent
还是偶尔的因为压力导致的
Or is it occasional and stress related?
我不  口吃
I don't... stutter.
我小时候曾经患有长期性的病理口吃
I had persistent pathological stuttering as a child,
但是可以通过语言障碍矫正解决
But it can be treated with rigorous speech therapy.
谢谢您  夫人
Yes, ma'am. Thank you.
为什么手术板上这里空缺
Why is this slot on the board blank?
我要在其他住院医师同事中挑一位
I need to select one of my fellow residents
填补这个空缺
For that slot.
这是我们这一届的第一个主刀手术
It's the first solo surgery of my class.
主任让你从同辈中挑选
The chief asked you to choose from your peers?
是的  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
帕特森先生
Mr. Patterson.
有些表格需要您妻子填写
I have some forms for your wife to fill out.
现在可以吗
Is now a good time?
她写博客
She's a blogger...
关于癌症和失语的
About cancer and voicelessness.
在网络上的圈子里她很有名
She's famous in certain internet circles.
看起来你们两位
Well, it seems like you two have
相处的很好
A-A pretty great system going here.
你们学会了如何交流
I--You've learned to communicate.
你是说那些便利贴
Oh, you mean the post-Its?
你觉得这是很好的交流方式
You think that's a pretty great system?
那  那很
I--It's...
方便
Convenient.
"是的" "不" "你好" "我爱你"
"Yes, no, hello, I love you"...
看久了
You read the words long enough,
他们就失去意义了
They begin to lose their meaning.
中间水平横向胫骨破裂
Mid-Shaft transverse tibia fracture?
抱歉打扰
Hi. Sorry to barge in.
我只是  只是路过  看到了骨折
I was, uh, I was just walking by, and I saw broken bones,
我爱骨折
And I love broken bones.
小于5度角  不是吗
Less than 5 degrees of angulation, right?
是的  那是
Yeah. It, uh...
我们可以用闭合复位术以及石膏治疗
Uh, we can treat it with... closed reduction and casting.
颈椎存在屈曲伸直
Flexion-Extension views of the cervical spine?
是的
Yes.
我  我要去看看我的病人
Uh, i-I sh--I should go see my patient.
是椅子
That's a chair.
看起来是心包积血
looks like a hemopEricardium.
通知心脏科
Let cardio know.
未来领袖在外面  她需要做CT
Hey, I've got a future leader outside. She needs a c.T.
你没投票给我我真的不生气
-Hey, uh  -Oh, I'm not mad at you for not voting for me.
-不然就像包庇我  -很好  你应得  克里斯蒂娜知道的
-It would've looked like you were playing favorites. -Good. You deserve it. Cristina knows that,
虽然你们在吵架
Even you two are fighting.
你和杨吵架
you and Yang are fighting?
我们没吵架  是曾经吵架  过去时
We're not fighting. Fought--Past tense.
多严重  很严重吗
How bad is it? Real bad?
她不行了
she's crashing.
脑部血液有问题
There's brain matter in the blood.
-通知手术室和心脏科  -她怎么了  好丽 好丽
-Let an O.R. Know we're coming and page cardio.  -what happened to her? Holly? Holly?
好丽  你们把我姐姐怎样了?
Holly? What did you do to my sister?!
好丽 好丽  你们把她怎样了?
Holly! Holly! What did you do to her?!
你知道我够格主刀手术
So... you know I deserve this.
你知道我是最有资格的
You know I'm the most qualified.
但我不想把事情搞得这么尴尬  我不想
But I don't want it to be a big, awkward thing. I don't.
所以  你知道  做你觉得正确的事
So just, you know, you do what you have to do.
好
Okay.
行
呆会儿见
I'll see you later.
我们这边准备可以了  艾玛
we're almost done here, emma.
好丽会好起来的  对吗  她会好起来吗
Holly, will be all right, right? She's gonna be okay?
她很快就被送进手术房  没事的
Well, she got into surgery very quick, so that's good.
我父母来了吗?
Are my parents here yet?
他们  他们在路上  你爸爸
They're--They're coming. Your dad's--
好丽会好起来的  对吗
But holly is gonna be all right, right?
她不会  不大会  死的对吗?
Uh, she's not in--In, like-- She won't die?
-艾玛  你是无心的  -我说了"我希望你死"
-Emma, you didn't mean it. -I said, "i hope you die."
这不可以是她听到我说的最后一句话  不可以
That can't be the last thing she heard me say. It can't.
求求你们  救救她
Just don't let her die. Please.
好  我去手术房看看  回来告诉你最新消息
All right, I'll go to the O.R. And get an update for you.
好吗
Okay?
好的
Okay.
杨医生  客观点
be objective, Dr. Yang.
对比他们的技术和成就
Consider accomplishments, achievements,
选出最突出的人
Look for the standouts.
现在  我们来看看
Right now, let's see
当我让他做接驳缝合时
What kind of standout Dr. Karev proves himself to be
克莱夫医生有什么突出之处
When I ask him to sew the graft.
真的
Really?
当然  杨医生  看紧克莱夫
Absolutely. Dr. Yang, watch Karev
看看他的技术能否做主刀手术
To see if his skills are up to par for the solo.
系统  设计一个系统
A system. Devise a system.
根据系统为每个人排序  就这么简单
Rank everyone accordingly. That's all.
谢谢
Thank you.
让开  发生什么事了  她的脑在变色
out of the way. What just happened? Her brain is changing color.
让开  让开
get outta the way. Get outta the way.
她在出血  注射100ml甘露醇
She's hemorrhaging. Push 100 of mannitol.
我做了什么  我做了什么
What did I do? What did I do?
听着  那个新的实习生  梅瑞迪斯的朋友
Ooh. Okay, okay. So the new intern, Meredith's friend--
-没阑尾的那个疯女人  -对  我们刚聊过
-The psycho with no appendix? -Yeah. We talked.
我的意思是  她走进来跟我说话
I mean, she came and talked to me,
但是看上去  不仅仅只是聊天  你懂的
But it was, like--It was more than that, you know?
一个人用某种眼神看着你  你懂的
A guy looks at you a certain way, you know,
他一边说话一边上下其"眼"  然后  你就清楚了
His eyes wander when he talks to you, and bang, you just know.
这是小女孩的表现  我实在搞不懂
But this whole girl thing, it's so confusing.
有身体接触吗
Well, was there touching?
-没有  -有拨弄头发吗
-No. -Was there playing with the hair?
-没有  -有舔嘴唇吗
-No. -Was there licking of the lips?
天啊  都是我自己想出来的
Oh, my god. I made it up.
我胡思乱想  因为我孤独沮丧
I made it up because I'm lonely and depressed
而且急需新来的辣辣实习生注意到自己
And desperate for attention from the hot new intern.
新来的疯实习生  疯狂  性感
Crazy new intern. Crazy, hot--
停  吸引人的都是制造麻烦的人
No! The hot ones are the ones that cause trouble,
她们会让你分心  发现不了自己真正的潜能
The ones that distract you from realizing your true potential.
你需要专注于医学
You need to focus on the medicine.
不要把精力浪费在被压抑的情欲上
Take all that pent up sexual energy you'd waste
不要去想那些年轻  性感  脱光光的实习生
Thinking about hot, young, naked available interns,
把精力用在你的聪颖的头脑上  说得对
And put it back into your genius... right.
用在你神圣的工作上
Your godliness.
为病人造器官  这才吸引
Build someone an organ. That's hot.
-她对我笑  我刚才给你说了吗  -不要再提实习生
-She smiled. Did I mention she smiled?  -No hot interns!
我们会把新造的软管插入
And then we'll insert the newly constructed tube
她的气管与食道中间某处
In between her trachea and esophagus
就像  这样
Just... like... that.
所以这里的阀门会打开
So this valve right here flips open
-当有空气流进她气管时  -你走进我的范围了
-When she has air in the trachea  -You're in my space.
后退  滚到后面去
Back up. Just back the hell up.
贝利医生  麻烦你给格雷医生找点事做
Dr. Bailey, will you please find Dr. Grey something to do
不要再在这里打扰了
Other than interfere?
格雷医生  去为帕特森医生准备好手术材料
Uh, Dr. Grey, finish prepping Mrs. Patterson for surgery.
她刚才走进我的范围了
She was in my space.
乔治  能帮我顶一会儿吗
George, can you cover for me for a little while?
你要去哪  我们忙不过来了
Where are you going? We're swamped.
我有事要做
Uh, there's something that I need to do.
-要紧事  好吗  -热辣辣的嘿咻
-It's pressing, okay?  -It's the hot sex.
她不想错过热辣辣的嘿咻  伊兹
She doesn't want to miss out on the hot, hot sex. Izzie--
佐治  门诊而已  你能应付过来的
It's the clinic, George. You can handle the clinic.
她出现在这  你算幸运了
You're lucky she even showed up.
她整个礼拜都没来这里
She hasn't been here all week.
谢博德医生
Dr. Shepherd--
不是你的错  她刚进行的可是颈动脉切除手术
It wasn't you. She had a carotid dissection.
你做什么也没用
Nothing you could've done.
但我们不能仅
So we can't just--
她脑血管大面积受伤
she had a massive c.V.A.
导致了大脑供血停止
The blood supply to her brain was cut off
而且无法复原
And cannot be restored.
所以即使谢博德医生修好了
So even though Dr. Shepherd was able to fix
她脑上的洞  使脑组织
The hole in her brain that allowed the brain tissue
不再从鼻孔漏出来
To leak through her nose,
但随后的颈动脉切除手术
The subsequent carotid dissection
使她丧失了脑部功能
Has caused loss of her cerebral function.
-你明白吗  -她脑死亡  我明白
-You do understand that?  -She's brain dead. I get it.
她仅仅16岁
She's only 16.
这是好消息
That's good news.
她所捐赠的器官都将会是很有价值的
She'll be an excellent candidate for organ donation.
很有价值的捐赠者  超有用的器官  年轻人
Excellent candidate. Excellent organs. Young.
伙计
Dude...
你的资格被剥夺了  政策把你给毁了
You were robbed. You got screwed by politics.
主任需要一个代罪羔羊  这不公平
The chief, he needed a scapegoat. It's so unfair.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我  我做不到
I-I can't do this.
我  我迫不得已时会拍马屁  但不是拍你的
I-I-I can kiss ass when I have to, but not yours.
下面  那个膝盖截肢手术
Uh... below-The-Knee amputation--
横向切开胫骨中间
Make a transverse incision at the mid-Shaft of the tibia,
取出骨膜
Elevate the periosteum
用骨锯锯开胫骨与腓骨
And cut the tibia and fibula with a bone saw,
绑上维管束  运行止血器
Ligate the vascular bundles and release the tourniquet.
我做过四个这样的手术了  一次是在尸体上  三次在旁候补
I've done four of 'em-- One on a cadaver, three on stan.
你知道要选谁了吗
You know who you're gonna pick?
我根据一个系统为他们排序
Well, I'm ranking them according to a system.
你知道的  手术技术  参与手术时间
You know, surgical skills, hours in the O.R.
出版的论文  学术造诣
Published papers, academic accomplishments--
你了解他们  了解他们的能力
You know them. You know their capabilities.
凭直觉选吧
Go with your gut.
直觉  我才不会单凭直觉把病人的性命
My gut? I'm not putting a patient's life
放在一个医术生疏的医生手上
In the hands of a novice surgeon
凭直觉对我可很奏效啊
Based on my gut.  well, it worked for me.
你的直觉
your gut?
我直觉告诉我选择你
It's what told me to choose you.
漂亮
Beautiful.
什么
what?
你的项链
Your necklace.
你说得对
Oh.  right.
我得走了
I have to go.
回见
See ya.
我希望你呼叫我不是要我帮忙递咳嗽滴剂
I hope you didn't page me to help you pass out cough drops,
-因为我不会这么做的  -伊兹在哪
-because it ain't gonna happen. -Where's Izzie?
我怎么知道  我以为她在这呢
How should I know? I thought she was here.
她在避我  她没有回复我的传呼
She's avoiding me. She won't answer my pages.
那你想我做些什么呢
So what do you want me to do about it?
你们现在一起  是吧
Well, you guys are together now, right?
那你能不能跟她聊一聊
So why don't you talk to her and find out
看看她为什么对自己的门诊置之不理
Why she couldn't care less about her own clinic?
你生气因为她不在
You're just pissed she's not here
因为你连几个流感病人都处理不好
because you can't handle a few cases of the flu.
她有点问题  阿历克斯  你得去跟她谈谈
Something's wrong, Alex. You need to talk to her.
-她不愿意跟我说话  -不要再提起伊兹了
-She won't talk to me. -Don't ever talk to me about Izzie again.
佐治而已
It's just George.
可那是你的朋友啊
Your friends, though,
你也知道  他们在争取一个机会
You know, they're out there fight for a chance
争取去截断那个人的脚
To chop off that guy's leg.
那是什么一回事
Wh-What is that anyway?
我们通过做手术学习
It's how we learn, by doing.
当主任让克里斯蒂娜决定我们命运的时候
And I lost my shot at the solo surgery
我就失去了主刀手术的机会
As soon as the chief made it Cristina's decision.
无论如何  总会有手术可做的
Anyway, there'll always be surgeries.
但是未婚夫死后归来并不常见哦
There won't always be fiancee who's come back from their dead
说得好
Good point.
你是不是要把这里的上皮去掉
aren't you going to deepithelialize here
然后接连气管
To connect it to the trachea?
贝利医生  你是个很好学的学生
You're a very eager student, Dr. Bailey,
很细心
Very thorough.
我随时为你服务
Any way I can be of service.
我并不感到抱歉
I'm not sorry.
什么
What?
我不为我们所做的感到抱歉
For what we did.
那很极端  也许甚至说很愚蠢
It was extreme, maybe even stupid,
但是这个计划
But this program?
我的意思是  下面拿手术刀的应该是你
I mean, you should be down in that O.R.
而不是在观看放坐着
Not up here in the nosebleeds,
我不应该整天重抄克莱夫的病历表
And I shouldn't be spending my entire day transcribing
就因为他的字难看到死
All of Karev's charts because his handwriting's illegible.
我想问  他教得怎么样
I mean, how is that teaching?
他们把我叫做莎迪小疯
So they can call me crazy sadie
天知道还有没有别的花名
And god knows what other names,
但是不可置否  这个计划破产了
But that doesn't change the fact that this program is broken.
他们只有在想和我们上床时
I mean, the only time they ever bother with us
才会来搭讪我们
Is if they think they can get us in bed.
并非这样
That's not true.
今天斯隆医生就教我不少知识
Dr. Sloan took the time to teach me today,
他并未谈及性事
And that was not about sex.
他喜欢你
he likes you.
谁  斯隆医生
Who? Dr. Sloan?
别否认你没发现  他总盯着你翘臀看
Oh, don't tell me you haven't noticed his eyes on your ass.
你真爱胡说
You are delusional.
他是不是切开她喉咙了
Is he cutting into her throat?
好血腥哦
Bloody hell.
我猜你将使用腐蚀测试
So I suppose you'll use a strip test
来确定在结合部有血流通过
To confirm flow across the anastomosis?
这样会损坏内皮组织的
That can damage the endothelium.
但你不想确认一下...
Oh, but don't you need to confirm--
贝利医生  干脆由你亲自
Dr. Bailey, would you rather do
来做帕特森太太的手术吧
Mrs. Patterson's surgery yourself?
-我走得了  -斯隆医生  我...
-I can leave. -Dr. Sloan, I w--
我并非质疑你的手术技能
I wasn't... questioning your surgical skills.
我只是想学习一些
I was just trying to learn...
高超的技巧  新兴的医术
Something exciting, something new.
住院医生到处忙活
I mean, these residents are running around
吵得不可开交
Fighting tooth and nail
只为了亲自为病腿截肢
For a chance to get to cut off a leg.
但看看  此时此刻的你
And... look what you've done here.
却是在创造原本没有的东西
You've--You've made something where there was nothing,
太令人激动了
And it's thrilling.
我只是要学习一下
I-I was just trying to learn.
谢谢  贝利医生
Thank you, Dr. Bailey.
要不要帮我把这块皮瓣
Now would you take the flap veins
连到内颈静脉上  如何
And join them to the internal jugular, please?
借过
Excuse me.
她看起来睡着了
She looks like she's sleeping.
我可以摸一下她吗
Can I touch her?
当然可以
Yes, of course.
能听到我说话吗
Can she hear me?
她能挺过来的  是吗
She can come out of it, right...
从昏迷中醒来
The coma?
-很多人都能醒来  -不  她不行
-People can do that?  -no, she can't.
很抱歉你们失去她了  但经测试
I'm very sorry for your loss, but tests confirm
你姐姐的身体机能依然完好
That although your sister's bodily functions are fine,
大脑已死亡
Her brain is dead.
没有意识  没有情绪  没有感知
She has no thoughts, no emotions, no senses.
我是dixon医生
I'm Dr. Dixon.
如果你父母同意的话
I will be harvesting your sister's organs
我希望能取出你姐姐的器官
If your parents agree.
拜托  她是我们的孩子  我们暂时无法接受
Please, she's our baby. We need more time.
对此我深表歉意
I'm very sorry for your loss,
但她的器官很年轻  此事攸关
But her organs are young and vital.
可以拯救很多人的生命
They could save many lives.
醒醒  好丽
Wake up, holly.
醒醒  快啊  快醒醒
Wake up. Come on. Wake up. Wake up. Wake up.
对于你们的遭遇我深表同情  但你姐姐不可能再醒来
I'm very sorry for your loss, but your sister can't wake up.
她已失去基本的生理功能  大脑已死亡
Her basic functions are gone. Her brain is dead.
虽然躯体依然存活  但不幸的是
Her body is alive, but unfortunately--
真的很不幸  她已经死了
Unfortunately, she is dead.
出去  你不能夺走她
Get out! You cannot have her,
不许你把她带走
And you cannot take her.
狄克逊医生  我想他们明白了
Dr. Dixon, uh, I think-- I think they understand.
我劝你先离开吧  拜托
I think you should go now, please.
此意虽有冒犯  但真的没时间了
I have offended you, but we are running out of time.
滚开
get out!
好丽  醒醒
Holly! Wake up!
快醒醒  好丽
Wake up, holly!
好丽  醒醒
Holly, wake up!
好丽  醒醒  求你了
Holly, wake up, please!
你有没有过自我幻想的性生活
Have you ever had mind-Blowing sex...
爽到让你欲仙欲死
The kind of sex that makes you want to die,
爽得滚到地上  无法自拔
Just fall on the floor and give up and die?
我正享有这种性事  是不是很棒
because this sex I'm having, it's that good.
这是我享受过的最棒的性事
It's the best sex I've ever had.
事实上  这是前无古人  后无来者的爽事
In fact, it's the best sex  anybody's ever had.
无法想像  享有这类爽事的人
I don't know why anybody who's had this kind of sex
-为何还有他求  -伊兹
-Would do anything but have sex. -Izzie...
我知道你会把手术交给梅瑞
You're gonna give the solo surgery to mer,
明显带有内幕交易的腐败色彩  很典型
Which is typical and boring and slightly corrupt,
但至少我拥有真正的
But at least I'm having, really, really...
令人爽翻的性爱
really good sex.
我只是告诉你一下而已
Yeah, I just thought you should know.
我知道你现在很紧张
Now I know you're nervous,
起初会感到很不适应
And it may feel a little strange at first,
但好歹试一下啊
But just give it a shot.
肯定还没忘记  来啊  你行的
You haven't forgotten. Come on. You can do it.
不
No!
不  不许再这样
No! No more!
不许再打字了  不许再用便条
No more typing! No more post-Its!
不许这样
No!
说话啊  跟我说话啊  该死的
Talk to me. Talk to me, damn it!
开口说话啊
Talk to me!
或许我们应该给她点时间
Okay, maybe we should give her a little time.
先生  最好你也离开一下
Um, sir, maybe you should go, too.
出去转一圈什么的
Just go for a-A walk or a drive.
再给她点时间
Just give her some space.
我给了她5年时间了
I've given her five years of space.
是我的错
It was my fault.
-你说什么  -那件事
-Excuse me? -What happened,
阑尾手术那件事  是我的错
The, um, the appy, it was--It was my fault.
我知道我参与其中  如果你要惩罚谁的话
I knew what I was doing, so if you want to punish someone,
-罚我吧  别罚杨医生  -你知道你父亲是谁
-Punish me, not Dr. Yang. -You know who your father is,
也是因为他  你才能留在此地
And you know he's why you're still here.
如果我是你
So if I were you,
我不会忙于担心那件事究竟是谁的错
I'd stop worrying about whose fault the appy was
而是努力做事
And start figuring out
来弥补过去犯下的错误
What I was gonna do to make up for it.
是的  谢谢  主任
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
有人正走向死亡
There are people dying.
正是现在  有人走向死亡
Right now, there are people dying.
这样是不对的
It's inappropriate.
对不起  快4点了  我要...
I'm sorry. It's almost 4:00, and I have to--
我必须要做决定了
I have to make this decision.
不  不  我没说你的事
No, no, I'm not talking about your system.
对于你的事我没意见  我说的是关于
I approve of your system. I was talking about
那个已脑死亡的女孩
The brain dead girl.
她听不到妹妹的呼唤  感受不到她的触摸
She can't hear her sister. She can't feel her hands.
现在有病人正走向死亡
There are patients dying right now,
而她的器官却可以拯救他们
And those organs would keep them alive.
别管太多感受  不要考虑什么科学
Leave feelings out of it-- Leave them out of the science,
不要管抉择是如何痛苦
Leave them out of the decision making--
因为与此同时  正有人濒临死亡
Because people are dying as we speak.
不是吧
Is she kidding?
恭喜你啊
Congratulations.
谢谢
Whatever.
有意思的抉择  杨
Interesting choice, Yang.
他最合适了
He made the best case.
伊兹
iz.
我赢了
I won.
现在几点了
What time is it?
杨  她选我来做主刀手术
Yang--She picked me for the solo surgery.
她决定了  太棒了
She did? That's amazing.
我爱你
I love you.
什么
What?
我爱你
I love you.
我爱死你了
I frigging love you.
我刚获得了主刀手术
I just got the solo surgery,
我第一个要告诉的就是你
And the first thing I did was look for you,
而你不在那儿
And you weren't there.
你根本就不在那里
You're never there anymore.
我一直在想
And I've been thinking about it,
我想可能是因为你也爱我
And i-I think it might be because you love me, too,
因为你害怕见到那一幕
And because you're scared of that...
因为我之前无法振作
And because i-I screwed it up last time
-因为丹尼死了  -阿历克斯
-And because Denny died and   -Alex--
听我说完
Just listen.
那个心脏病人  让你想起了丹尼
You had that heart patient, and it reminded you of Denny
并痛苦至极地
And how bad you felt
躺在厕所的地上
When you were lying on that bathroom floor.
我知道  我知道你害怕
I get that. I get that you're scared.
但你不会再有那样的经历了
But you're not gonna have to feel like that again,
因为我不会死的  伊兹
because I'm not gonna die, iz.
我再也不会欺骗你
And I'm not gonna cheat on you
我不会离开去任何地方
And i--I'm not gonna go anywhere...
因为
because...
因为你就是我梦中的情人
I think you're my best shot at...
只有与你相随  我才能表现得更好
I think with you, you make me better.
只有你能鼓舞我前行
You make me want to be better.
只有你能激励我攀登高峰
You make me want to be good.
我觉得我行
And I think I can.
和你在一起  我能勇往直前
With you, I think I can.
我不会去任何地方  你也不用再躲闪了
So I'm not going anywhere, and you can stop hiding.
你要是觉得害怕  没事儿
And if you want to be scared, that's okay.
我和你一起面对
Just be scared with me.
和我一起在我的第一次主刀手术中
Be scared while you scrub in with me
一起面对害怕
For my first solo surgery.
好吗
Okay?
你爱我
You love me.
得了
Shut up.
主刀手术啊
Solo surgery. Whoo.
我真开始讨厌那家伙了
I'm really starting to not like that guy.
我真的太不应该对你说那话了
I never should've said it.
我不是故意的
I didn't mean it.
我压根不该开口的
I never should've said it.
告诉她
Tell her that.
告诉她你最想让她最后听到的话
Tell her the last thing you'd want her to hear.
因为你要相信  如果是你躺在这
Because you have to believe that if it were you in this bed
而好丽却痛苦万分地坐在这的话
And Holly was sitting with your feeling this bad,
你也会原谅她的
You would forgive her.
告诉她
Tell her.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的很对不起
I'm so sorry.
我爱你
I love you.
她也爱你的
She loved you, too.
不管你说过什么
No matter what you said,
不管你们之间发生过什么
No matter what happened between the two of you,
她过去爱你
She loved you.
现在爱你
She loves you.
一直都爱你
你是  对的
So you were... right.
克里斯蒂娜和我吵架了
Cristina and I are fighting.
你该去  跟她谈谈
You should go, talk to her.
她是你的死党
She's your best friend.
这很重要
It's important.
德瑞克
Derek?
当你成为了医生之后  他们就不会告诉你
They don't tell you when you become a doctor
就像现在这样
It's gonna be like this.
他们不会告诉你  日后...
They don't tell you that you're gonna...
在你手中死去的病人远比你救活的多
Lose more patients than you save.
16岁
16.
我厌倦了死亡
I'm sick of the death.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我在家等你
I'll see you at home.
好的
Okay.
没事儿  没人在这儿
It's okay. Nobody else is here.
就只有我而已  我不过就是个实习医生
It's just me, and I'm just an intern.
我是个无名小卒  你尽管尝试好了
I'm nobody. So you can try.
要是没成功  也没关系的
And--And if it doesn't work, it's okay.
就试一下
Just--Just try.
嗨
Hi
狄克逊医生  今天过得怎么样呀
Dr.Dixon. How has your day been?
西雅图圣恩医院有没有给你一种家的感觉
You feel like you may have a home here at Seattle Grace?
杨医生  你今天折磨她了
Dr.Yang-- You tortured her today.
让她在她的同伴之间做选择
Making her choose among her peers,
某种精神折磨  那是你的主意吗
Some kind of emotional torture, was that your intention?
是的
Uh, Yes.
你的黑板能给我更好的安排吗
Have your board make me a better offer.
我们在冷战  而我不想
We're fighting, and I don't want to be.
让这都过去吧
Let's just put this past us.
不管主任还有实习医生之间发生过什么
What happened with the chief and the interns,
这都不重要
It doesn't matter.
我知道你就是为了那个不选我的
I know that's why you didn't choose me,
所以才会感情用事了
And I know that's why you made it personal,
让生活继续吧
So let's just move on.
是你在感情用事
You made it personal.
此时此刻  是你在感情用事
This, right here, is you making it personal.
之前你让我按原则做事  我才选阿历克斯
You told me to do what I had to do, so I chose Alex.
他是准备的最充分的
He was the most prepared.
所以我没选你
That's why I didn't choose you--
不是因为我们吵架  因为我不像你
Not because we're fighting, but because... unlike you,
我能把个人感情和
I can separate my personal life
工作分开
From my job.
你感情用事了
You made it personal.
你们什么屁话都别说
None of you said anything.
那些都是我们的实习生
Those were all our interns.
我获胜了
But I won this.
是他们选的我
They picked me.
如果我都没得到主刀手术的话
If I don't deserve this solo surgery,
没人得的到
Then none of us do.
我不知道是我太嫉妒阿历克斯
I don't know if I'm more jealous of Alex
还是太关心伊兹了
Or worried about Izzie.
我觉得她不对劲  小梅
I think there's something wrong with her, Mer.
我们都不对劲  乔治
There's something wrong with all of us, George.
是阿历克斯
That's Alex.
别在这
Not here.
这
Here.
你呼我
Hi. You paged?
是的  我需要你做我的助理
Yeah. I need you to scrub in with me.
伊兹在哪
Where's Izzie?
我吓坏了  我吓死了
I'm freaking out. I'm freaking out.
我告诉她  我爱她
I told her I love her.
我在主刀手术之前  我告诉她我爱她
I told her I love her before a solo surgery.
我真不敢相信  谁还会这么做
I can't believe that. Who does that?
她不会出现了  而我却又吓傻了
And now she's not gonna show up,and I'm freaking out
停  别犯傻了
Stop. Stop freaking out.
你要是搞砸了  害死了这家伙
If you screw this up and kill this guy,
我会发火的
I'm gonna be pissed.
到那时我也会知道  该我赢这个才对
Then I'll know I should've won it.
你得进去竭尽全力  阿历克斯
You have to kick ass in there, Alex.
你没得选择
You have no choice.
隆重之夜啊  克莱夫  你准备好了没
Big night, Karev. You ready?
准备好了吗
You ready?
他准备好了
He's ready.
我们这是去哪
Where are we going?
别担心  你会喜欢的
Don't worry. You'll like it.
来吧
Come on.
等等  就一会
Wait. Just wait.
等会儿
Wait.
没事儿的
It's ok.
感觉很棒  对吧
It's good,right?
这是通风口
It's the vent.
它清空你大脑了吧  感觉好多了  对吧
It clears your head. You feel better, right?
是的  是啊
Yes. Yeah.
这儿超越时间  超越空间
It's out of time, out of space.
在这儿的通风口  什么都能发生
Anything can happen in the vent.
任何事
Anything.
譬如说呢
Like what?
等待便知
Just wait.
你让她说话了
You made her speak.
帕特森夫人  她说"嗨"了
Mrs.Patterson-- She said "hi."
她说话了  你让她说话了
She spoke. You--You made her speak.
我尊敬你
I respect you.
无论是一个男人
As a man...
一位外科医生还是一名老师
A-As a surgeon, as a teacher,
我都尊敬你
I respect you.
所以
So...
教我
Teach me.
你这是在干嘛  别这样  住手
What are you doing? Don't do that. Stop.
教我
Teach me.
停下来
Stop.
-教我  -我们不能这么做
- Teach me.  - We can't do this.
你是小格蕾  而我也承诺过
You're little Grey, And--And--And I promised,
而且我还是你老师
And I'm your teacher.
那么你就  教我啊
So... teach me.
莱西
Ah, Lexie...
教我
Teach me.
不是吧  我真的差成这样
Come on. Am I really so bad?
不是
No.
是我差
I am.
我们孤身来到这个世界
We enter the world alone
并且孤身离开
And we leave it alone.
两者间发生的所有事
And everything that happens in between?
我们将之归功于为了要找寻伴侣
We owe it to ourselves to find a little company.
押50赌他开始10分钟之内向主任求助
$50 says he calls on the chief in the first 10 minutes.
押100赌他开锯之前喘不过气
$100 he chokes before they turn on the saw.
那个人可是我们的一员  给点尊重好不好
Hey, that's one of us down there. Show some respect.
我们需要帮助  我们需要支持
We need help,we need support.
否则我们将孤身奋战
Otherwise we're in it by ourselves...
陌生的人们
Strangers...
彼此隔绝
Cut off from each other.
而我们也终将遗忘
And we forget...
彼此间的相互联系
Just how connected  we all are.
相反的是  我们选择爱人
So instead, we choose love...
我们选择生活
We choose life...
而就有那么片刻
And for a moment...
我们会觉得  不是如此孤单
We feel just a little bit less alone.
10号刀
10-Blade.